here's an amazing geometric structure
called the fanel plane start with seven
points laid out like this by a line we
meet a collection of three points so
draw these seven lines note that the
final one is actually going to look like
a circle even though it's just a
collection of three points we see that
there are three points on each line and
there are three lines through each point
we can realize this structure using the
three-dimensional Vector space over Z2
the points correspond to the non-zero
vectors in the vector space so they
correspond to the onedimensional linear
subspaces the lines correspond to the
two-dimensional linear subspaces and
that means each line consists of three
vectors that coordinate wise add up to
zero mod 2 you can check that the three
vectors on each line as highlighted here
do in fact add up to zero mod 2 when you
perform coordinate wise addition this is
the world's smallest projective geometry
and it shows up in a lot of places in
mathematics